「良医」前情回顾
Previously on "The Good Doctor"...
你得缓口气  让头脑清醒
You need to take a break, clear your head.
你需要休假
You need a vacation.
我要辞职
I'm gonna quit my job.
我不想搬去
I'm not looking forward to moving
宾夕法尼亚州  郝尔希镇
to Hershey, Pennsylvania.
我不想要孩子
I don't want kids.
永远
Ever.
我因为殴打同事被解雇了
I've just been fired for physically assaulting an employee.
做吧  把我们分开
Go ahead. Chop us in half.
她们什么时候能醒过来
When will they wake up?
按理说这时候应该已经醒了
They should've already.
我们很担心你  珍妮
We were worried about you, Jenny.
你醒了就太好了
So glad you're back.
我跟你说三个词
I am gonna give you three words.
努力记住
Try to remember them.
苹果  球体  房子
Apple. Ball. House.
你能算一百递减七吗
Can you count back from 100 by 7 for me?
我可是要念哈佛的人
I'm going to Harvard, you know.
93 86
93, 86,
79 72 65
79, 72, 65.
我们在哪座城市
And what city are we in?
圣何塞
San Jose.
刚才是哪三个词
And what were those three words?
苹果  球体  房子
Apple. Ball. House.
要当心了  哈佛
Look out, Harvard.
我们要做更多检查以确保万无一失
We'll be doing a lot more tests to know for sure,
但你的心音听上去好多了
but your heart does sound better.
凯蒂呢
How's Katie?
你比她先醒  现在还很难说
You woke up before her, so too soon to tell.
几乎没有阿尔法或贝塔脑电波
There's virtually no alpha or beta brain activity.
肯定是分离手术时哪里疏忽了
We must have missed something during the separation surgery.
没有
We didn't.
凯蒂的血压稳定  血氧饱和也正常
Katie's BP was steady, sats were fine,
区域供血也恢复了
regional blood supplies were reconstructed.
跟珍妮一样  只是她醒了
Just like Jenny, yet she's awake,
凯蒂还在昏迷
Katie's in a coma.
凯蒂移植了新的矢状血管
Katie's got the new sagittal graft.
她的情况可能是由那条血管的血流问题造成的
A problem with blood flow in that vein could cause her condition.
核磁共振血管造影应该能显示移植血管是否通畅
An MRI angiogram should tell us if the graft is open or not.
大家好
Hello.
我来做血管造影
I will proceed with the angiogram.
莫菲  你两天没来了
Murphy, you've been gone for two days.
不如先说说这事
How about we start there?
好
Okay.
就算你跟院长说了
Just because you talked to the president
也不算批准休假
doesn't qualify as permission.
好  没错
Okay. Yes.
下次我跟我女友旅行时
I...will notify Dr. Melendez
会通知到梅伦德斯医生的
next time I go on a road trip with my girlfriend.
有意思
Amazing.
「旅行」
"Road trip"?
格拉斯曼医生说你是去处理私人要事了
Dr. Glassman said you were dealing with a personal crisis.
没错
That is true.
你知道「私人要事」的意思吗
Do you know the definition of personal crisis?
知道  一系列事件中的一个
Yes. A stage in a sequence of events
决定未来所有事情的走向的阶段
at which the trend of all future events is determined.
-是指死亡  生病  -对
- A death, an illness. - Yes.
旅行可不算
No, not a road trip.
好
Okay.
你和布朗医生去给凯蒂做血管造影
You and Dr. Browne get going on Katie's angiogram,
除非你又有私人要事要处理
unless, of course, you have any personal emergencies to attend to.
没  我的要事解决了
No. My crisis is over.
进来
Come in.
双胞胎怎么样了
How are the twins doing?
珍妮在恢复中
Jenny's in recovery.
各项数据正常  也能说话了
Her numbers look good. She's talking.
凯蒂  情况不太好
Katie -- not so good.
我们得聊聊莫菲
We need to talk about Murphy.
我说了他请私人事假了
I told you he's on personal leave.
对  但他可不是这么说的
Yeah, well, that's not what he said.
你跟他聊了
You talked to him?
对
Yes.
五分钟前在外科病房聊的
In the surgical unit five minutes ago.
这是我们为凯蒂移植的矢状血管
There's the sagittal vein graft we constructed for Katie.
血流通畅
It's open with good flow.
移植血管正常
Graft is fine.
这样的话  我们还是没法解释她为什么昏迷
Which means we still have no explanation for her coma.
放大一点
Go in closer.
大脑中静脉
The middle cerebral vein,
流出大脑的血液不足
it has low flow out of the brain.
你是说流出不足就代表流入不足
You're thinking low flow out means low flow in?
对  我就是这意思
Yes, that is what I'm thinking.
应该看看动脉流入期
We should look at the arterial inflow phase.
我们想看看动脉流入期  麻烦了
We'd like to look at the arterial inflow phase, please.
你们在路上做了什么
So, what'd you do on your trip?
有时我们去旅行
Well, sometimes - when we take a road trip,
是为了逃避什么
we're running away from something.
我吻了莉亚
I kissed Lea.
格拉斯曼医生生我的气了
And Dr. Glassman is mad at me.
他为什么生你的气
What is he mad at you about?
几乎全堵住了
It's almost entirely blocked.
威利斯环出现了畸形
And...there's a malformation in the Circle of Willis.
凯蒂的大脑几乎没有供血
Katie is barely getting any blood to her brain.
抱歉  肖恩
Excuse me. Shaun?
能跟你聊聊吗
May I speak with you, please?
梅伦德斯医生没有生气
Dr. Melendez -- He was not angry.
不  肖恩  梅伦德斯医生生你的气了
Oh, no, Shaun. Dr. Melendez is angry with you.
他也生我的气了
He's also angry with me.
为什么
W-why?
「为什么」  因为我替你撒谎了
"Why"? Because I lied to him for you.
你为什么跑了
Why did you run away?
我没有跑
I didn't -- didn't run away.
你没通知你的主治医生就走了
When you leave without notifying your attending,
撇下在医院的一切职责...
when you drop all of your responsibilities at this hospital...
你没跟包括我在内的任何人说就走了
When you leave without telling anyone, including me,
那就是跑了
then you are running away.
跟那姑娘去旅行有帮助吗
Did this trip with this girl help?
有  有  有帮助
Yes. Yes, it did.
好  怎么回事
Okay. How?
我会提前两周通知的
I would like to give two-weeks notice.
良     医
第一季  第十二集
妈妈  能让他们再拿些碎冰吗
Mom, can you ask them to bring me some more ice chips?
我去拿  宝贝
I'll get them, sweetie.
我去叫医生
I'll get a doctor.
不用
No.
我只是...
I'm just...
你走了后  这里就没人了
When you left, there was no one here.
这是我生平第一次独自一人
For the first time in my life, I was alone.
宝贝
Sweetie.
感觉很...冰冷
It felt...cold.
有时确实很冰冷
Well, sometimes it is cold.
知道吗
But you know what?
某天你或许会爱上这感觉
Someday, you might find that you like it.
非法解雇
Wrongful termination.
卡卢医生打了一位主治医生
Dr. Kalu assaulted an attending surgeon.
我想这在法律上也站不住脚
I don't think you have strong legal footing here.
背后有隐情
There's more to the story.
尼尔
但愿宝刀未老  我应该还能执教少年足球吧
我很同情卡卢医生
And I am sympathetic to Dr. Kalu,
但他也不能因此就打人
but his ends don't justify his means.
显然我们不能容忍职员...
Obviously we can't tolerate staff members --
可你容忍了
And yet you do.
请看完
Please read on.
大脑中动脉狭窄
The middle cerebral has narrowed.
直径不足两毫米
It's less than 2 millimeters.
我们绕过动脉  恢复血流
We bypass the artery here and restore blood flow.
切开后脑吗
Open her back up?
她才动了一场大手术
She's just been through a massive operation.
大脑组织还没稳固
The brain tissue hasn't settled.
再动一次手术很可能会让她中风
Another could very well stroke Katie out.
其他办法
Other options.
血管内
Intravascular.
做血管内超声波也没法
I don't see how an intravascular ultrasound
看得更清楚
gives us a better picture.
不是影像
No, not imaging.
他是想在血管造影室给大脑中动脉
He wants a stent in the middle cerebral artery
安装血管支架  好主意
in the angio lab. I like it.
通常只有心脏和颈动脉才做血管支架
Stenting is usually reserved for the heart and the carotid.
是不常见  但这个病例本身就很罕见
It's not the usual, but we are way past the usual.
这确实会降低中风的概率
It would lower the danger of a stroke.
莫菲医生  想来协助吗
Dr. Murphy, would you like to assist?
好
Y-Yes.
梅伦德斯医生  你想给我写封
Dr. Melendez, would you like to write me
推荐信吗
a letter of recommendation?
看见那段狭窄了吗  就在大脑中动脉
You see the narrowing there, in the horizontal segment
-水平段  -大脑中动脉
- of the middle cerebral artery. - Middle cerebral artery.
对  我听说过你
Yeah. I've heard about you.
老手见到你都会紧张
You're the one making the old guard nervous.
我为什么会让人紧张
W-why would I make people nervous?
因为你有天赋
'Cause you have a gift.
而医生们会拿同行做比较
And surgeons judge themselves against their peers,
现在  你处于领先
and right now, you're winning.
我们就位了
We're in position.
莫菲医生  麻烦给球囊通气
Dr. Murphy, please inflate the balloon.
再打一次造影剂
Give us another squirt of contrast.
血流应该已经恢复
And we should have good blood flow.
近端动脉出现夹层
Yes, the proximal end of the artery is dissecting.
球囊损伤了她的动脉
The balloon is damaging her artery.
波形图显示正在恶化
Waveform is worsening.
不能用支架了
Stent won't hold.
她会中风的  停止手术
She's gonna stroke. I'm aborting.
好
Okay.
波形图恢复正常
Waveform is normalizing.
我们又回到了起点
We're right back where we started.
凯蒂的脑部仍处于缺血状态
Katie's brain is starving.
我想见凯蒂
I want to see Katie.
我知道她还处于昏迷中  我还是得见她
I know she's in a coma. I still need to see her.
我想她
I miss her.
我们不能让你俩冒着感染的风险
We can't risk contamination for either of you.
她需要知道我在那
She needs to know I'm there.
我们明白
We understand.
你们不明白
You can't understand.
没人能明白
No one can.
我们总是相互支持
We have always been there for each other,
现在是她最需要我的时候  我却不在
and now when she needs me most, I'm not there.
你刚经历了一场四十小时的手术
You've just been through a 40-hour surgery.
我们需要你关注你自己的康复情况
We need you to focus on your own healing.
她的心脏呢
And what about her heart?
我们准备做一个心导管插入术测试
We're going to do - a cardiac catheterization test
看看她的心脏循环状况有没有改善
to see if her heart circulation has improved.
注入造影剂  看一下心脏血液供给情况
Inject the contrast to evaluate the heart's blood supply.
我的灵魂看起来怎么样
How's my soul looking?
那是另一门学问了
That's a different specialty.
凯蒂说眼睛是灵魂的窗户
Katie says the eyes - are the window to the soul.
我说眼睛会撒谎  心才是灵魂的窗户
I say the eyes lie. It's the heart.
那么  目前来讲你的灵魂看起来不错
Well, then, so far your soul is looking good.
强壮  血液通畅
Strong, unobstructed blood flow.
脑室造影照片会告诉我们肌肉功能的情况
Ventriculogram will tell us how the muscle function's doing.
这么安静  一切还好吗
So quiet. Is everything okay?
心室僵紧扩张
Ventricle's strained and dilated.
我们本希望在分离后有所改善
We were hoping for some improvement post-separation,
但它几乎不运作了
but it's barely pumping.
没道理啊
It just doesn't make any sense.
分离手术本应
The separation was supposed
缓解珍妮心脏的压力
to relieve the stress on Jenny's heart.
需求减半  工作量减半
Half the need, half the work.
珍妮的心脏甚至比看起来还弱
Jenny's heart was even sicker than it appeared.
我们没料到这种情况
Seems we couldn't see that
因为凯蒂的心脏承担了所有珍妮心脏的工作
because Katie's heart was doing all the work for Jenny's.
我们应该怎么做
What can we do to fix it?
移植一个新的心脏
Give her a new heart.
我们不可能能及时找到匹配的捐赠者的
We're not gonna find a donor match in time.
能  我们已经有能和珍妮匹配的完美的心脏了
Yes, we already have the perfect heart for Jenny.
同卵双胞胎  所以是匹配的
The sisters are monozygotic and therefore a genetic match.
但是凯蒂还活着
On the other hand, Katie is alive.
-她三度昏迷  -她的心脏还跳动
- She is GCS-3. - Her heart is still beating.
是  但是她已经无反应了
Yes, but she is unresponsive.
我不知道怎么让血液流回大脑
And I don't see a way to return blood flow to the brain.
十之八九  凯蒂不会醒过来了
In all likelihood, Katie's not coming back.
是  凯蒂很有可能会死
Yes, Katie very well may die,
但是我们无法预测是什么时候
but we can't predict when that'll be.
可能是今天  也可能是二十年后
It could be today. It could be 20 years from now.
如果凯蒂一直使用呼吸机的话
If Katie stays on the ventilator.
-那不是我们能决定的  -我知道
- That's not up to us. - I know.
但我还知道  基于这些片子
But I also know that, based on these scans,
珍妮可能撑不过今晚了
Jenny might not make it through the night.
我们得把这个告诉她妈妈
We need to propose this to the mother.
凯蒂不可能醒来了吗
There's no chance Katie will wake up?
我们不敢百分之百肯定
We can't say with 100% certainty,
但据我们在凯蒂的脑部扫描片子上看到的...
but from what we saw on Katie's brain scan...
我们几乎不抱希望
we have little reason for hope.
但是我们可以肯定
But what we can say with certainty
没有凯蒂的心脏  珍妮会死
is that without Katie's heart, Jenny will die.
能等等吗
Can we wait?
再等一等  也许你们能了解更多信息
Just a little. Maybe you'll know more.
也许会有所改变
Maybe something will change.
如果我们什么都不做的话
If we don't do anything,
珍妮的心脏在明早之前就会停止跳动
Jenny's heart will stop before the morning.
你们怎么...
How do you...
会痛吗
Would it be painful?
不会的  我们会关掉凯蒂的呼吸机
No. We simply power down Katie's ventilator.
一旦没有了设备维持生命  她就会平静离开的
Once off life support, she will peacefully pass.
你想让我们跟珍妮解释吗
Do you want us to explain this to Jenny?
我相信她想要在场
I'm sure she'll want to be present.
不
No.
我在她们很小的时候就教育她们
I put trust in them from an early age,
让她们相信责任会增强力量
thinking responsibility would build strength.
我觉得是有用的
I think it worked.
但是这个...
But this...
不
No.
无论如何珍妮不能知道这件事
Jenny can't be part of this in any way.
这会毁了她的
It'd destroy her.
我会告诉她凯蒂死了
I'll tell her Katie died.
「肖恩·莫菲医生
"Dr. Shaun Murphy
展现出超出他年纪的技术能力」
exhibits technical skills beyond his years."
你写的
You wrote that?
是
Yes.
所以我在底下签上了我的名字
That's why I signed my name at the bottom.
你觉得肖恩能在别的医院生存下去
You think Shaun survives at another hospital?
我觉得他在这都生存不下去
I didn't think he'd survive here.
没你的推荐  肖恩哪也去不了
Without your endorsement, Shaun isn't going anywhere.
我可能不太看得惯他
I may have my issues with him,
但是无论这个想法有多愚蠢
but no matter how stupid an idea this may be,
我不会阻止他去追求他想要的
I'm not gonna stop him from going after what he wants.
我旁边还有一个签名档
There's another signature line next to mine.
是医院院长签字的地方
It's where the president of the hospital has to sign.
首席肿瘤科医生
The chief oncologist.
这是在我来之前发生的  12月14日
This is before I came here in December of '14.
马歇尔医生在一次术后讨论时
Dr. Marshall shoved a scrub nurse
推了一个器械护士
during a post-op discussion of some sort.
你记得吗
Do you remember that?
记得
I do.
你的回应是和护士和解
Your response - was to settle with the nurse
而马歇尔医生则得到了一个警告
while Dr. Marshall - was let off with a warning.
那年的早些时候还有件几乎一样的事例
There's another almost identical instance earlier in that year.
在这两件案子中  有问题的医生都是白人
In both cases, the doctors in question were white.
他们仅受到了批评  而卡卢医生被解雇了
They were censured. Dr. Kalu was fired.
你觉得  这是种族问题
You think - this was a racial matter?
你觉得我种族歧视
Do you think I'm racist?
我更偏向白人
That I favor white people?
那为什么那时候宽大处理  现在却不行
Then why the leniency then and not now?
他们是明日之星...
They're stars...
碰巧是白人而已
that happened to be white.
像马歇尔那样的医生让圣何塞圣文德医院
Doctors like Marshall allow St. Bonaventure
有能力和西海岸的其他机构竞争
to compete with other West Coast institutions.
所以  那就是我们的辩词
So, that's our defense?
「我们不是种族歧视
"We're not racist.
我们只是允许我们的医生殴打他人
We just allow our doctors to assault people
只要他们能带来足够多的捐赠人」
as long as they bring in enough donors."
他们被惩戒了
They were reprimanded.
也没有再生事端
And there were no further incidents.
你觉得这套说辞在法庭上有用吗
And how do you think all of this is gonna play out in court?
和解
Settle.
好
Okay.
去几层
Floor?
四层
Four.
肖恩问梅伦德斯医生要了推荐信
Shaun asked Dr. Melendez for a letter of recommendation.
我知道
Yeah.
我只要签字  他就可以走了
All I have to do is sign it and off he goes.
我觉得...
I think...
他可能认为你生他的气了
he might think that you're mad at him.
如果你不签  就更加证实了他的想法
If you don't sign, it reinforces what he thinks.
但是如果你签了
But if you do,
会让他知道你是相信他的
it lets him know that you believe in him.
我能摸摸她吗
Can I touch her?
当然
Of course.
再见  宝贝
Goodbye, baby.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Are you ready? - Yes.
她稳定下来了
She's stabilizing.
我不明白
I don't understand.
怎么了
What's going on?
凯蒂还不想死
Katie's not ready to go.
她能自主呼吸了
She's breathing on our own,
也就是说凯蒂的脑干功能是正常的  对吗
which means Katie has normal brain stem function, correct?
当移除呼吸机的时候  生命是可以继续
When a ventilator is removed, life can continue.
很少见  但是的确是可能的
It's rare, but it can happen.
这也改变不了对她清醒的预后
It doesn't change the prognosis for awakening.
移除了呼吸机  生命体征正常
Off the ventilator with normal vitals
也就是长期处于植物人状态  是吗
suggests long-term vegetative state, right?
是的
Yeah.
这个办法不行了
We just lost our remedy for Jenny's heart.
体外膜肺氧合呢
What about ECMO?
用机器作为珍妮心脏的替代品
Use the machine as a replacement for Jenny's heart.
能给我们争取两周的时间
Buys us... two weeks of life?
我不喜欢这个提议
I don't like it.
体外膜肺氧合需要用到血液稀释剂
ECMO requires blood thinners.
她刚做完脑部手术
She just had brain surgery.
这样可能会造成大出血
It could cause a catastrophic bleed.
体外膜肺氧合和可能出现的并发症
Well, ECMO and its complications
也许是我们唯一的办法了
may be our only avenue.
重新把她们连接起来
R-Re-conjoin them.
你想把她们的头部重新连接起来吗
You want -- You want to put their heads back together?
不是头部
Not the heads.
是大腿  股动脉
The thighs, the femoral vessels.
很好笑吗
Is it a funny idea?
我觉得很好笑  我居然没想到这个办法
I think it's funny - that I didn't think of it.
两个女孩的血液是完全一样的
The girls' blood is identical.
不用打抗血栓的药物  不会引发出血
No need for anti-clotting meds, so no possibility of a bleed.
一旦她们被连接
As long as they're attached,
凯蒂的心脏就能为珍妮供血
Katie's heart will beat for Jenny.
如果凯蒂去世了
When Katie dies,
我们就切断她们股部的血管连接
we sever the femoral connection
将凯蒂的心脏移植给珍妮
and transplant Katie's heart into Jenny.
我们刚花了四十个小时将她们分开
We just spent 40 hours separating them,
现在我们又要将她们重新连接到一起
and now we want - to put them back together.
你想让凯蒂死去
You tried to kill Katie?
不
No.
你们撤掉了她的生命支持系统
You took her off life support.
你觉得这是什么
What do you call that?
仁慈  不仅仅是对于她
Mercy. Not just for her.
如果没有新的心脏  你就会死
You need a heart or you're going to die.
凯蒂还活着
Katie's alive.
她本来就活着  现在更有生命力了
She was then, and she's even more now.
凯蒂活着只是指她的器官功能还没有衰退
Katie's alive in the sense that she has basic organ function,
但她的大脑没有任何高级认知活动
but she has no higher-cognitive brain activity.
她尚且留有一口气
She's surviving,
但不能算活过来了
but she is not living.
几个小时前
Hours ago,
直到你要终止她的生命时
you thought she'd die
你还觉得她会死
as soon as you pulled the plug.
你判断错了
You were wrong.
我怎么知道你这次没有判断错呢
How do I know you're not wrong this time, too?
凯蒂现在处于昏迷状态
The demand on -- on Katie's heart
她对心脏的需要是很小的
is minimal in her resting state.
她要帮你是很轻松的
She can easily tolerate helping you.
我不想让凯蒂做我的生命支持机器
I won't ask Katie to be my life-support machine.
安德鲁斯医生
Dr. Andrews.
让她们姐妹俩在一个房间过夜吧
Let's put the sisters in the same room overnight.
我觉得珍妮没有把自己看作一个独立的个体
I don't think that Jenny sees herself as an individual yet.
我觉得唯一能让珍妮改变想法
You know, I'm thinking the only thing that'll change Jenny's mind
重新跟凯蒂连接在一起的只有凯蒂
about the reattachment is Katie.
让她们俩靠近些也许能让珍妮看见
Being close might help Jenny to
凯蒂已经撑不了多久了
see her as lifeless.
也可能会起到反作用...
Could backfire...
让她更加觉得自己在亲手杀死她姐姐
and cement her feelings that she's killing her sister.
是有这种可能
Yeah, possibly.
反正现在的状况也好不到哪儿去
And then we're in the same position anyways.
好吧  就按你说的办
Okay, do it.
那这个棒球呢
Well, what about baseballs
这是本姑娘在巨人队比赛的时候拿到的
that this girl caught at a Giants game
亨特·彭斯还在上面签名了
signed by Mr. Hunter Pence?
虽然他没击过这个球  但也无所谓
He didn't hit it, but that doesn't matter.
-体育用品放在哪儿  -这儿
- So, where is the sporting-goods one? - There.
不  这个不放在体育用品里
Oh, no, that does not go in sporting goods.
不放在那儿吗
It doesn't?
我在申请去宾夕法尼亚州  郝尔希镇
I'm applying to move my residency to
继续做住院医生
Hershey, Pennsylvania.
真的吗
Really?
是的  宾州州立医疗中心
Yes. Penn State Medical Center.
你是跟着我去宾州的吗
Are you following me?
我得确保你这么做
I need to make sure
不仅仅是为了离我近一些
you're not just doing this to stay close to me.
不是
No.
肖恩
Shaun.
我想过属于我自己的生活
I want my own life.
我想掌控自己的生活
I want a life that I control,
而不是被格拉斯曼医生控制
not Dr. Glassman.
格拉斯曼医生只是想帮你
Dr. Glassman is just trying to help you.
我不想要别人帮我
I don't want help.
但如果...你真的需要帮助呢
But what if... you need help?
如果我待在这里  我怎么知道是不是呢
How will I know if I stay?
东西太多了  你东西太多了
Too much stuff. You have too much stuff.
※更多精彩内容敬请关注※公众号:安安神叨叨
我们应该安排一次旅行
We should book a trip.
或许可以去个暖和点的地方
Maybe somewhere warm.
你动作太慢了
You are so slow.
你就叠叠内衣而已  内衣叠起来多方便
You're only folding underwear. Underwear's easy.
好吧
Okay.
别  尼尔  我不想...
No, Neil, I don't want to...
好吧
Fine.
开始吧  普莱斯顿
Let's go, Preston.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
开始
Go.
你是我这一天里唯一的美好
You're the only good thing about my day.
我昨晚夜不能寐
I couldn't sleep last night.
我连眼睛都没法闭上  直到...
I couldn't even close my eyes until...
我能用手感受到凯蒂的心脏跳动
I could feel Katie's heart beat in my hand.
如果我们重新连接在一起
If I do this,
某种意义上来说凯蒂的心脏会为我跳动  是吗
at some point Katie's heart will beat for me, right?
计划是这样的
That's the plan.
那无论我走到哪儿  她会永远陪着我
Then wherever I go, she will always be with me.
好吧  我同意
Okay. I'll do it.
你感觉怎么样  珍妮
How you doing, Jenny?
我没任何感觉
I can't feel anything.
这是局部麻醉药的效果
That would be the magic of local anesthetic.
血管都夹住了  好了  医生们
Vessels are clamped. Okay, Doctor.
准备开始进行血管吻合术
We're ready to proceed with the anastomotic grafts.
完成了  是吗
It's done, isn't it?
我能感觉得到
I can tell.
请把两姐妹的生命体征放到一起
Let's put both the girls' vitals next to each other, please.
加把劲啊
Come on now.
给她们几个心动周期的时间调整
Give it a few cardiac cycles to adjust.
我们怎么样
How'd we do?
你们很棒
You did great.
为什么去郝尔希镇
Why Hershey?
莉亚要搬去那儿了
Lea is moving there.
那儿的糖块挺好吃的
Well, they-- they make good candy bars.
我不喜欢糖块
I don't like candy bars.
我喜欢吃煎饼
I love pancakes.
那儿也有煎饼
Well, they make those, too.
我把你带来这儿是因为...
I brought you here because...
我觉得这儿可以锻炼你的能力
I thought this place would provide a challenge for your abilities.
但我发现我带你来这儿的真正原因
But I realized I really brought you here
是我觉得你会需要我
because I thought you needed me.
这封推荐信我已经签好名了
This is a now signed letter of recommendation.
但是...
But...
我不想让你走
I don't want you to go.
如果你留下来  我会退让  我会...
If you stay, I'll-- I'll back off. I'll...
我会让你自己做选择  自己去犯错
I'll let you make your own choices, your own mistakes.
我相信你  肖恩
I believe in you, Shaun.
她们的血压下降了
Their blood pressure dropped.
下降了五毫米汞柱
5 millimeters of Mercury.
我喜欢听你说「我们」
I like when you say "Their."
的确可能会有一些波动
You're gonna see some fluctuation.
每过一个心动周期  血压都下降五毫米汞柱
BP drops 5 millimeters every complete cardiac circulation.
如果有波动不应该是不规律的吗
Shouldn't the fluctuation be inconsistent?
也许凯蒂的心脏不像预想的那样
Maybe Katie's heart isn't picking up
能承受得住珍妮的负荷
the workload for Jenny as expected.
珍妮
Jenny.
BGM: Break Apart (feat. Rhye) by Bonobo
珍妮
Jenny.
我  我在这儿呢  凯蒂
I'm-- I'm right h-here, Katie.
就在你旁边
Right next to you.
♪ It's hard to take all of this hate ♪
♪ It's hard to take all of this ♪
跟莫菲一起给凯蒂做个快速的全套检查
Take Murphy and get a shotgun work-up on Katie.
我要心电图  脑电图  各项化验等等
I want everything -- EKG, EEG, and labs,
再给珍妮做个超声心动图
and an echo on Jenny.
♪ This hate ♪
凯蒂的脑电图上的阿尔法节律显示她已经苏醒了
Katie has an awake alpha rhythm on her EEG.
她真的很棒
She's doing remarkably well.
我们还没有完全确定
We're still not entirely sure
是什么导致凯蒂苏醒的
what caused Katie to regain consciousness.
把她们重新连接到一起
Attaching them again could
将血液输向了珍妮的身体
have redistributed fluid into Jenny's system,
可能也减少了凯蒂脑部的肿胀
possibly decreasing the swelling in Katie's brain.
说不好
Just don't know.
我知道
I know.
她们需要彼此  一向如此
They need each other. They always have.
现在的问题变成了是珍妮和她的心脏
The issue right now has become Jenny and her heart.
当凯蒂昏迷的时候
When Katie was in a coma,
她心脏的新陈代谢需求是很低的
the metabolic demand on her heart was very low,
但现在她醒过来了
but now that she's alert and active,
心脏负荷不了她们两个的身体运作
there just isn't enough heart for both of them.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
我们还在等化验结果
We're awaiting test results.
我们不确定凯蒂的心脏
We're not sure how long Katie's heart
还能负担珍妮的身体多久
can tolerate the strain of supporting Jenny's circulation.
我们会一直通过实验室的化验报告和
We'll closely monitor them with
心动图密切监测她们
cardiac labs and echoes.
我们要尽快为珍妮找到一颗心脏
We need to find a donor heart for Jenny as soon as possible.
不行
No.
「不行」
"No"?
我的首席执行官的工资只有你赔偿金的一半
I've had CEOs settle for half of what I just got for you.
我不在乎钱
I don't care about the money.
这很好  甚至很令人钦佩
That's beautiful. It's admirable, even.
但是  事情就是这样
But, you see, this is how it works
因为我们生活在一个文明的社会
because we live in a civilized society --
他们伤害了你
they hurt you,
我们就以牙还牙  用一笔巨额支票来讨回公道
we hurt them by making them cut you a massive check.
我不想以牙还牙
I don't want them to hurt.
我想让他们把工作还给我
I want them to give me my job back.
「找回你的工作」的三分之一
A third of "Your job back" Is,
对我来说  什么都不是
by my calculation, uh, almost nothing.
我会付给你这笔赔偿金的三分之一
I'll pay you - a third of this settlement.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你付给我的钱比你一年赚的都多
You'll be paying me more than you earn in a year.
我想找回我的工作
I want my job back.
午餐你请客
Lunch is on you.
午餐我请客
Lunch is on me.
你为了和莉亚在一起搬到宾夕法尼亚州
Are you moving to Pennsylvania to be with Lea?
她知道吗
Does she know that?
莉亚知道我要搬到郝尔希镇
Lea knows I'm moving to Hershey.
是  但她知道你是为了她
Yeah, but does she know you're going there
才搬到那去的吗
because she is going there?
我不是为了她
I'm not.
莉亚让我感到幸福
Lea makes me happy.
莉亚不是唯一一个可以让你感到幸福的人
Well, Lea's not the only one that can do that.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
你们的脑利钠肽结果
Your BNP.
珍妮·昆克尔的心脏蛋白水平很...
Jenny Kunkler's - cardio protein levels are...
我从没见过这样的结果
I've never seen anything like it.
这是因为这是两颗心脏的蛋白水平  不是一颗
That's because the levels are for two hearts, not one.
珍妮在杀死凯蒂
Now Jenny is killing Katie!
-发生了什么  -我们现在要把她们分开
- What's going on? - We got to separate them now
-否则她们两个都要死  -双胞胎送过来了吗
- or we're gonna lose them both. - We got the twins on the way?
在路上
In transit.
JL在路上进行了局麻
J.L.'s gonna do a local on the fly.
听我数  三  二  一
On my count. Three, two, one.
我们不能分开  你会死的
We can't do this. You'll die.
我们得做
We're gonna do it.
不行
No.
我们得一起决定
We're in this together.
我们一直都是这样
The way we've always been.
我们永远都会这样
The way we were meant to be.
是珍妮  她出现室颤
It's Jenny! She's in v-fib!
立刻推注一毫克肾上腺素
Push a milligram epinephrine now!
准备人工通气
Prepping Ambu bag.
莫菲  开始胸外按压
Murphy, start chest compressions!
是珍妮
It's Jenny.
她的心脏已经彻底衰竭
Her heart had nothing left to give.
凯蒂呢
Katie?
她的情况稳定了
She's stable.
她的生命体征平稳
Her vitals are good,
但是还有个问题  我们需要你的帮助
but we have an issue that we need your help with.
是什么
Okay.
凯蒂不让我们把她和珍妮分开
Katie won't allow us to separate her from Jenny.
如果她不同意  凯蒂就会血液凝固致死
If she doesn't acquiesce, Katie will clot and die.
一万单位注射
Bring 10,000 units on board.
我们出去  让你们单独谈谈
We'll clear out - and give you some privacy.
孩子
Baby.
我们得让她离开了
We have to let her go.
我不会让他们把我们分开
I won't let them separate us.
我一直都不想
I never wanted to do this.
你总是说  我们这样连在一起是有原因的
You used to say we were made this way for a reason.
我不会让他们把我们分开
I won't let them do this.
就算这会害死我
Even if it kills me.
我想让你看看你姐姐
I want you to look at your sister.
看看她
Look at her.
我不能同时失去两个女儿
I can't lose both of my daughters.
安德鲁斯医生  晚上好
Dr. Andrews. Evening.
我看了双胞胎的档案
I, uh, checked out the twins' file.
这个病例简直不可思议
It's an amazing case.
先说清楚  杰瑞德
To be clear, Jared,
我觉得你不应该出现在这里
I don't want you here.
我向普莱斯顿小姐说的都是事实
What we presented - to Miss Preston was the truth.
这我明白
I understand that.
而那些待解决的医生以及医生自我监督的问题
And those problem doctors and the ways we police ourselves will be dealt with,
早就该解决了
should have been dealt with a long time ago,
但你越界了
but you stepped over a line.
我是为了我的工作
I fought for my job.
你出卖了正直的品性
You compromised your integrity.
你和那个混蛋科利的事
The incident with that jerk coyle had nothing to do
和种族没有任何关系
with black or white,
那只是你和你的律师为了利益而找的托词
but that's what you and your lawyer sold for leverage.
当你歪曲种族主义就为了某些...
And when you misrepresent racism for something it's not...
...让我们各退一步
...it sets us two steps back.
她准备好了
She's ready.
杰瑞德  你负责抽吸
Jared, you're on suction.
梅氏解剖剪
Mayos.
BGM: Someone To Stay by Vancouver Sleep Clinic
♪ You were alone ♪
♪ Left out in the cold ♪
♪ Clinging to the ruin of your broken home ♪
我很冷
I'm cold.
♪ Too lost and hurting ♪
♪ To carry your load ♪
♪ We all need someone to hold ♪
♪ You've been fighting the memory all on your own ♪
去钓鱼
Gone fishing.
♪ Nothing worsens, nothing grows ♪
商店关门了
Store's closed.
我跟克莱尔谈过了
I spoke to Claire.
♪ I know how it feels being by yourself in the rain ♪
♪ We all need someone to stay ♪
♪ Hear you, falling and lonely, cry out ♪
♪ Will you fix me up? ♪
♪ Will you show me hope? ♪
♪ At the end of the day, you were helpless ♪
♪ Can you keep me close? ♪
♪ Can you love me most? ♪
我想和你分手
I want to break up.
为什么
Why?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
用这个理由分手太奇怪了
Odd reason to break up with somebody.
我希望你能拥有生命中的一切
I want you to have everything in your life.
包括孩子
Which includes kids.
告诉过你了  我可以不要孩子
I told you - I was willing to not have kids.
某一天你会因为这个决定而后悔的
You're gonna regret that decision one day.
-我不会的  -你会的
- I won't. - Yes, you will.
你只是为了面子而不去想  但你以后会的
You're just too decent to think it, but you will.
那又怎么样
So what?
我们都有后悔的事
We all have regrets.
我  我还想过去太空人队当三垒手呢
I-I wanted to play third base for the Astros.
这不一样  那是儿时的梦想
It's not the same. That is a child's dream.
这是你的人生
This is your life!
这也是我的人生
This is my life,
而且被你怨恨远比我心碎
and it'd be more devastating to be resented by you
更让我难受
than to have my heart broken.
而且你会是一个好父亲
And you are going to be a great dad.
肖恩
Shaun.
我有东西要给你
I wanted to give you something.
我把这个借给你
I'm letting you borrow it.
等你来看我的时候带着
Bring it when you come visit?
好的
Okay.
向我保证
Promise?
你会来看我的  对吗
You're gonna come visit, right?
我保证  我喜欢郝尔希镇
I promise. I like Hershey.
-你还从来没去过郝尔希镇呢  -莉亚在那
- You've never been to Hershey. - Lea's there.
我能抱抱你吗
Can I put my arms around you?
你是个好医生吗
Are you a good doctor?
因为当我想你的时候
'Cause when I think of you,
我就会想到你是个好医生
I think you are.
♪ You were alone ♪
♪ Left out in the cold ♪
♪ Clinging to the ruin of your broken heart ♪
♪ You were falling and lonely, cry out ♪
♪ Will you fix me up? ♪
♪ Will you show me hope? ♪
♪ At the end of the day, you were helpless ♪
♪ Can you keep me close? ♪
记住  我说的是借
Remember, I said borrow.
♪ Can you love me? ♪
♪ I know how it feels being by yourself in the rain ♪
♪ We all need someone to stay ♪
♪ Hear you, falling and lonely, cry out ♪
♪ Will you fix me up? ♪
♪ Will you show me hope? ♪
♪ At the end of the day, you were helpless ♪
♪ Can you keep me close? ♪
※更多精彩内容敬请关注※公众号:安安神叨叨
♪ Can you love me most? ♪